

(985) 696-4781

chadlefort@gmail.com

github.com/ChadLefort

chadlefort.com

I've always had a strong passion for web development. I enjoy the feeling of accomplishment when programming, and I take pride in writing maintainable and efficient code. Committed to team success, I prioritize delivering exceptional products that provide an outstanding user experience. Over the 11 years of my career I've specialized in frontend solutions. I've architected and delivered a wide range of revenue growing projects while leveraging a variety of modern frameworks and libraries. Additionally, I've set up and managed different configurations and created build pipelines for projects that have resulted in cost efficiency and improved productivity. One project that I recently worked on had substantial growth across all aspects of the website with significant increases in user engagement ranging from 325% to 9564% over 90 days.

Job Experience

CDIT

Senior Frontend Engineer

December 2020 - Present

Built and architected a new mobile first dashboard, membership cart, and a live instructor-guided online education SaaS platform for dentist and their practices using Vue 3, TypeScript, Nuxt, and GraphQL.

In less than 2 years, launched 3 major high-impact projects that set speed and quality standards for the development team and brought measurable success for a client. One project witnessed substantial growth across all aspects of the website with significant increases in views, clicks, and user engagement, ranging from 325% to 9564% over a 90 day period.

Revitalized a registration cart by enhancing user experience, reducing friction points, and introducing promotional code functionality which exceeded new membership signup goals by 25%.

Helped build a new platform in React for a VOIP SaaS and migrated modules from NPM packages to Webpack Module Federation to allow for a better Microfrontend architecture. This improvement helped with challenges such as application updates, deployments, and reduced the number of pull requests needed from 5 down to 1.

Veriforce

Senior Frontend Engineer

July 2017 - December 2020

Architected several projects in React, Redux, TypeScript, and Material-UI and wrote unit tests with Jest and React Testing Library for a contractor management SaaS platform.

Saved hours of manual deployment time by creating a monorepo with Lerna for 17 React projects and 6 NPM packages leading to cost efficiency and improved productivity for a team of 7 frontend developers.

Oversaw and mentored a team of 5 frontend developers to complete 3 major revenue-growing projects ahead of schedule by having pair programming sessions and code reviews regularly.

Advocated for UI and code consistency by creating design patterns and managing dependency upgrades, enhancing app stability and user experience.

Migrated existing React projects to TypeScript which laid out the structure and configuration for future React projects.

Netchex

Full Stack Software Developer

November 2014 - July 2017

Developed applications using domain driven design with C# for REST APIs and created single page applications using AngularJS, TypeScript, and Bootstrap for a payroll, benefits, and human resources SaaS platform.

In 3 months led a project to build a mobile first onboarding dashboard to be released and presented at the company's annual client facing conference.

Developed a custom reporting single page application using AngularJS for 6,000+ clients, enhancing their accounting and business

Edison Chouest Offshore

Programmer

December 2013 - November 2014

Built a tool to organize and store excel spreadsheets for logic controller's configuration files using Node.js, Express, MySQL Bootstrap, and jQuery.

South Central Planning and Development Commission

Software Developer Intern

February 2013 - November 2013

Built a custom contact form using PHP, Bootstrap, and jQuery to guide customers in resolving their issues and reduce support calls.

Developed 2 client sites using WordPress, Bootstrap, PHP, and jQuery.

Skills





TypeScript



















Material-UI

Education

Nicholls State University

Bachelor of Science (B.S.)

August 2009 - December 2013



Majored in Computer Information Systems

GPA: 3.6

Awards

Consistently been awarded the President's List award since the Fall 2010 semester. The President's List award requires a student to maintain a scholastic GPA of 3.5 or higher.

Organizations

Member of Beta Gamma Sigma. It is the highest recognition a business student anywhere in the world can receive in a business program accredited by AACSB International.

Member of Upsilon Pi Epsilon. It is the first and only existing international honor society in the Computing and Information disciplines.